Guide to the W.H. Cowley Papers SC0196
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Personal papers and writings, Series 1
  - Correspondence, writings and speeches, 1922-1978; Series 1B
    - "Student Mores as Environmental Influences," The Proceedings of 12th Annual Meeting of New York Association of Deans, Bulletin No. 8 pages. 23A-33A. Given at Union College. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy of this., 1938 Nov 10-12 (Box 10, Folder 38-40)
    - Newsclippings about WHC talks in Utica, Cleveland, Boston, New York, and Clinton., 1938 Dec (Box 10, Folder 38-41)
    - Review of WHC's OSU career., 1929-1938 (Box 10, Folder 38-42)
    - Papers related to WHC's arrival at Hamilton College and the accident he had the first night in the president's house., 1938 (Box 10, Folder 38-43)
    - "The College President as a Leader," WHC article, American Association of Colleges Bulletin, 5 pages., 1938 (Box 10, Folder 39-1)
    - Interview with WHC by Duncan, C. William of the Philadelphia Evening Ledger on leadership., 1938 Jan 18 (Box 10, Folder 39-1A)
    - "European Influences Upon American Higher Education, WHC article, Educational Record, pages 165-190., 1939 Apr (Box 10, Folder 39-2)
    - "A Challenge to Leadership, WHC address opening the college, Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 9-13., 1939 Sep (Box 10, Folder 39-3)
    - "The Liberal Tradition and Student Personnel Work," WHC speech given for the Association of Virginia Colleges, 10 pages. (Box 10, Folder 39-4)
    - "To the Student Body," WHC speech, Hamilton life., 1939 Jun 10 (Box 10, Folder 39-5)
    - "The History and Philosophy of Student Personnel Work," transcript of WHC speech given at the Cleveland Conference, pages 7-10., 1939 May (Box 10, Folder 39-6)
    - WHC study outline for Professor Graves, Edgar B. to use in visiting eleven other colleges, 50 pages., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-7)
    - "Occupational Orientation of College Students," ACE brochure written by WHC and others, 76 pages., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-8)
    - Honorary degree citations given by Hamilton College to Hayes, Helen; Eckstein, Gustave; Kaltenborn, Hans V.; Root, Elihu Jr.; Peabody, Bishop; and Pound, Ezra. See also 39-13., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-9)
    - Correspondence with Milton Mayer about his Harper's article and WHC's alleged criticism of Hutchins., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-10)
    - "The Clientele of American Higher Education," WHC speech, Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 124-127., 1939 Mar (Box 10, Folder 39-11)
    - "Hamilton College Survey, Volume One: Admissions," WHC report, 152 pages., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-12)
    - Same as 39-12 with 70 pages supplement., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-12A)
    - Professor Edgar B. Graves' 10 page letter to WHC reporting on 39-12. See also 39-7., 1939 Jun 15 (Box 10, Folder 39-13)
    - "Summary of the Alumni Study," 23 pages., 1939 May 27 (Box 10, Folder 39-14)
    - "The University in the United States of America," WHC article included in The University Outside Europe edited by Bradby, Edward pages 37-112., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-15)
    - WHC report to the Board of Trustees., 1939 Apr 15 (Box 10, Folder 39-16A)
    - WHC report to the Board of Trustees., 1939 Jun 9 (Box 10, Folder 39-16B)
    - WHC report to the Board of Trustees., 1939 Oct 14 (Box 10, Folder 39-16C)
    - WHC review of Paul W. Chapman's Occupational Guidance, ERB, page 28. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy of this., 1939 Jan 4 (Box 10, Folder 39-17)
    - "Should Education be Strictly Mental?" transcript of WHC talk given in Fairfield, Conn. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy of this., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-18)
    - "Holism, A Philosophy of Education," transcript of WHC talk given for the Pennsylvannia Deans of Women, 4 pages., 1939 Feb (Box 10, Folder 39-19)
    - "They Need Jobs," WHC article, Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 187-188., 1939 May (Box 10, Folder 39-20)
    - "Charge to the Class of 1939", transcript of WHC address, plus newspaper reports in the Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 244-45. (Box 10, Folder 39-21)
    - "The President's Report," Hamilton Alumn; Review, pages 231-235., 1939 Jul (Box 10, Folder 39-22)
    - Correspondence with Gavit, J.P. regarding four Hamilton College fraternity members who stole two cars., 1939 Mar (Box 10, Folder 39-23)
    - Transcript of WHC speech welcoming visiting physicists to Hamilton., 1939 Apr 1 (Box 10, Folder 39-24)
    - "The College in a Democratic Society", newsclippings about Dartmouth Conference., 1939 Apr (Box 10, Folder 39-25)
    - WHC message printed in the Hamilton and Union College football game program., 1939 Nov 18 (Box 10, Folder 39-26)
    - Job specifications for a chemistry professor and a dean of students at Hamilton., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-27)
    - Memo on WHC's admission study faculty meeting. See aslo 39-12 and 39-12A., 1939 Dec 11 (Box 10, Folder 39-28)
    - Newsclippings regarding miscellaneous WHC speechs and and interviews given., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-29)
    - Correspondence with Tead, Ordway about WHC as possible candidate for the presidency of the City College of New York., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-30)
    - Correspondence, citation and program brochure regarding Hobart College's award of an honorary L.H.D. Degree to WHC., 1939 May (Box 10, Folder 39-31)
    - Miscellaneous papers., 1939 (Box 10, Folder 39-32)
    - "The History and Philosophy of Student Personnel Work," report of the 17th Annual Meetings of the American College Personnel Association St. Louis, Journal of the National Association of Deans of Women, pages153- 162., 1940 (Box 10, Folder 40-1)
    - "The Constancy of Regents' Grades," WHC article, School and Society, pages 239-240., 1940 Sep 21 (Box 10, Folder 40-2)
    - "Fire Always Makes Room for Itself," WHC speech, Vital Speeches of the Day, pages 87-90., 1940 Nov 15 (Box 10, Folder 40-3)
    - "Two Gentlemen of Union," transcript of WHC speech given at Union College, 2/21/40. Sigma Xi Quarterly, pages 69-73., 1940 (Box 10, Folder 40-4)
    - "A New Admission Plan," WHC article, JHE, pages 345-352., 1940 Oct (Box 10, Folder 40-5)
    - "The Current College Admissions Situation," WHC article, Educational Record Supplement, pages 34/46., 1940 Jan (Box 10, Folder 40-6)
    - "An Historical and Statistical Analysis of College Admissions Criteria," WHC article, Association of American Colleges Bulletin, pages 522- 558., 1940 Dec (Box 10, Folder 40-7)
    - "The Educated Man Concept in the Twentieth Century," WHC address given at Skidmore College, School and Society, pages 345-350., 1940 Oct (Box 10, Folder 40-8)
    - "A Memo to the Committee on Ways and Means About Tuition Charges," WHC memo, Hamilton College, 27 pages., 1940 Jan 20 (Box 11, Folder 40-9)
    - "The Challenge to Freedom," transcript of WHC address given at the Pratt Institute, 11 pages., 1940 Oct 2 (Box 11, Folder 40-10)
    - "Major Trends and Developments During the Last Decade," WHC speech given at the Eastern College Personnel Officers Conference at Amherst College. Proceedings of the Eastern College personnel Officers, pages 25-39., 1940 Oct (Box 11, Folder 40-11)
    - WHC memo to the gymnasium campaign committee, Hamilton College, 65 pages., 1940 Feb 26 (Box 11, Folder 40-12)
    - President's Report, Hamilton College, Hamilton College Bulletin, Vol. 23, No.3., 1930-1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-13)
    - Papers regarding the Hamilton College commencement of 1940 including the birth of Cowley, Ellen on that day. Includes letters of congratulations and newsclippings., 1940 Jun-Jul (Box 11, Folder 40-14)
    - "President's Senior Questionnaire," Hamilton College, 16 pages., 1940 Mar (Box 11, Folder 40-15)
    - "The Fraternity - Whence and Whither," Outline of WHC talk given at the Alpha Delta Phi Convention, Chicago., 1940 Sep 7 (Box 11, Folder 40-16)
    - "Intelligence and Spirit," WHC address given at the University of Buffalo, 10 pages plus newsclippings., 1940 Jun 12 (Box 11, Folder 40-17)
    - "National Defense and Self-Discipline," WHC speech given as opening address, Hamilton College, 9 pages Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 19-24., 1940 Sep-Oct (Box 11, Folder 40-18)
    - "What Now?" WHC address given at Kenmore High School, 12 pages., 1940 Dec 11 (Box 11, Folder 40-19)
    - "Hamilton College Survey, Vol. Two: Curriculum," 238 pages, Oversize., 1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-20)
    - "An Outline of an Educational Philosophy," Hamilton College Survey, Vol. 2, Part II, chapters 4-7, 76 pages., 1939-1943 (Box 11, Folder 40-20A)
    - Letters about 40-20., 1939-1943 (Box 11, Folder 40-21)
    - Papers concerning the Jessup Survey of the Social Sciences at Hamilton College." See also 41-20., 1940-1941 (Box 11, Folder 40-22)
    - List of seven books suggested by WHC for Herb West's "Hanover Browsing" article in the Dartmouth Alumni Magazine, 1 page., 1940 Nov (Box 11, Folder 40-23)
    - WHC review of Freeman Butts' The College Charts Its Course, Survey Graphic, page 474., 1940 Sep (Box 11, Folder 40-24)
    - WHC foreword to Ike Lovejoy's So You're Going to College., 1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-25)
    - WHC report to the Hamilton College Board of Trustees., 1940 Jan 20 (Box 11, Folder 40-26)
    - WHC report to the Hamilton College Board of Trustees. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1940 Feb 20 (Box 11, Folder 40-27)
    - WHC report to the Hamilton College Board of Trustees. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1940 Jun 14 (Box 11, Folder 40-28)
    - WHC report to the Hamilton College Board of Trustees. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1940 Oct 12 (Box 11, Folder 40-29)
    - Honorary degree citations conferred by Hamilton College on Robeson, Paul, Alumni Magazine, page 69. Wolcott, Coykindall, Snyder, Lambert, Littauer, Shephard, Alumni Magazine, pages 204-211., 1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-30)
    - Correspondence with Horner, Harlan H. offering WHC the position of New York State Commissioner of Education., 1940 Jan (Box 11, Folder 40-31)
    - Correspondence with Hamilton trustee, Thompson, Harold W. about Hamilton College admissions proposal. Includes letter from Thompson, H. and WHC memo., 1939, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-32)
    - "Hamilton College Announces," a pamphlet describing the new admmissions procedures, 3 pages., 1940 Jun (Box 11, Folder 40-33)
    - Newspaper reports of WHC switching support with Fox, Dixon Ryan from FDR to Willkie, Wendell., 1940 Aug-Sep (Box 11, Folder 40-34)
    - Statement against students having automobiles, one paragraph, source unknown., undated (Box 11, Folder 40-35)
    - News report of convocation address given by WHC at the University of Minnesota., 1940 Dec 20 (Box 11, Folder 40-36)
    - Copy of WHC memo to Root, Elihu Jr. about complications regarding the new admissions plan, Hamilton, 2 pages. See also 40-32., 1940 Jan 4 (Box 11, Folder 40-37)
    - Hamilton College Chapel prayers., 1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-38)
    - Correspondence with Thurstone, L.L. about the Hamilton College Survey, Vol. II: Curriculum and Faculty Psychology., 1940 Jun-Aug (Box 11, Folder 40-39)
    - Correspondence with Stryker, Lloyd about the ideals of Hamilton, Alexander., 1940 Apr (Box 11, Folder 40-40)
    - Papers regarding Carnegie Foundation Grant and summary report., 1940, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 40-41)
    - Hamilton College Publications. Similar volumes for the years 1942-43 have been sent to the Hamilton College Library. Oversize., 1938-1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-42)
    - Hamilton College Minute Book. Similar volumes for the academic years through 1942-43 have been sent to the Hamilton College Library., 1940-1943 (Box 11, Folder 40-43)
    - Miscellaneous folders:, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 40-44)
    - Honorary degree awarded to singer Robeson, Paul newsclipping., 1940 Jan (Box 11, Folder 40-44A)
    - Correspondence abut WHC election to alumni membership in the New Hampshire chapter of Phi Beta Kappa., 1940 Mar (Box 11, Folder 40-44B)
    - Newsclippings reporting the addition of Knudson, Charles A. (classmate at WHC's at Dartmouth) to the Hamilton College faculty., 1940 Sep (Box 11, Folder 40-44C)
    - "Education and National Defense," WHC speech delivered at the 35th Annual Convention of the Association of Life Insurance Presidents, 14 pages., 1940 Dec (Box 11, Folder 41-1)
    - "Destruction and Construction," WHC address delivered at the 130th Hamilton College Opening. Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 3-10, and the American Association for Colleges Bulletin, pages 619-625., 1941 (Box 11, Folder 41-2)
    - "Mid-twentieth Century Discipline," WHC address given at the fall commencement of the University of Minnesota, 1940. Reprinted in Minnesota Chats, Vol. 23, No.6, 3 pages., 1940, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 41-3)
    - This number was inadvertently skipped. (Box 11, Folder 41-4)
    - "Should Dentists be Educated?" WHC speech, Journal of the Dental Society of the State of New York, pages 7-13., 1941 Sep-Oct (Box 11, Folder 41-5)
    - "The Fallacy of Intellectualism," WHC article, Aim, pages 3-9., 1941 Jul (Box 11, Folder 41-6)
    - "The Large Place of the Small College," WHC speech given at the 77th convocation of the University of the State of New York. pages 26- 41., 1941 Oct (Box 11, Folder 41-7)
    - Minutes of a special Hamilton Board of Trustees meeting., 1941 Apr 14 (Box 11, Folder 41-8)
    - Description of work expected of Drought, Neal E. as WHC research assistant., 1941 Nov 1 (Box 11, Folder 41-9)
    - Description of work expected of Diggs, Robert M. as WHC research assistant., 1941 Sep 26 (Box 11, Folder 41-10)
    - Hutchins, Cowley and Pope Pius XI, WHC article by Schwinn, Bonaventure, OSB, Catholic World, pages 22-29., 1941 Oct (Box 11, Folder 41-11)
    - Correspondence with Morris, L.G. about football, and the hiring of Evashevski, Forest as head coach., 1941 Feb 8 (Box 12, Folder 41-12)
    - Correspondence with Jewett, S.O. Secretary., 1941 Feb-1942 Dec (Box 12, Folder 41-13)
    - "A Confidential Statement Concerning the Presidency of the University of Minnesota." Also contains transcript of telephone conversation with the University of Minnesota. See also 41-19., 1941 Feb (Box 12, Folder 41-14)
    - WHC's 1939-40 report to the Hamilton Board of Trustees, 23 pages., 1940 Dec-1941 Mar (Box 12, Folder 41-15)
    - "Hamilton, a Small College," WHC article, Upstate Monthly, 2 pages., 1941 Nov (Box 12, Folder 41-16)
    - Newsclipping about WHC address to IBM on creative thinking in business, Business Machines, 2 pages., 1941 Sep 2 (Box 12, Folder 41-17)
    - Correspondence with Root, Elihu Jr. about the Hamilton presidency. Also contains WHC letter to Root. See also 38-38., 1938, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-18)
    - Correspondence with University of Minnesota officials and Hamilton officials about invitation to WHC to become President of the University of Minnesota., 1940 Jan-1941 Mar (Box 12, Folder 41-19A)
    - Correspondence with friends and colleagues about University of Minnesota presidency offer., 1940 Jan-1941 Mar (Box 12, Folder 41-19B)
    - Newsclippings about University of Minnesota presidency offer., 1941 Feb (Box 12, Folder 41-19C)
    - Correspondence with Morrill, J.L. about the presidency of the University of Minnesota., 1940 Nov-1941 Feb (Box 12, Folder 41-19D)
    - "Social Science Survey Committee Report," Hamilton College. Includes joint report, 15 pages and individual reports of five social science committee members. Also includes one page explanation of Social Science Survey's organization written by WHC., 1940, 1941, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 41-20)
    - Dean Restine, F. H. memo to WHC concerning holism and the administration of Hamilton, 37 pages., 1941 Jan 22 (Box 12, Folder 41-21)
    - "Democracy as Self-Discipline," WHC address delivered at Mt. Hermon School, 11 pages., 1941 Jun 28 (Box 12, Folder 41-22)
    - Job specifications for five Hamilton faculty positions, 9 pages., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-23)
    - "Hamilton College Faculty Evaluation," 3 volumes. Oversize., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-24)
    - WHC review for the JHE of Roethlisberger and Dickson's Management and the Worker. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy. (Box 12, Folder 41-25)
    - Hamilton College Alumni Fund pamphlet, inserted in the Hamilton Alumni Review. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-26)
    - Hamilton College honorary degree citations, Hamilton Alumni Review. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1941 Jul (Box 12, Folder 41-27)
    - "Charge to the Class of 1941," Alumni Review. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1941 Jul (Box 12, Folder 41-28)
    - Hamilton College Board of Trustees Report., 1941 Jan 25 (Box 12, Folder 41-29)
    - Hamilton College Board of Trustees Report., 1941 Apr 19 (Box 12, Folder 41-30)
    - Hamilton College Board of Trustees Report. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy of this., 1941 Oct 11 (Box 12, Folder 41-31)
    - Hamilton College Board of Trustees Report., 1941 Jun 13 (Box 12, Folder 41-32)
    - News reoprts of WHC dinner after turning down the University of Minnesota Presidency., 1941 Apr 20 (Box 12, Folder 41-33)
    - WHC speech at dinner for new Utica Superintendent of Schools., 1941 Sep 30 (Box 12, Folder 41-34)
    - Prayers written to use in the Hamilton College Chapel., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-35)
    - "To the Class of 1941," WHC article, Hamiltonian, edited by Peach, Robert E. page 7. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy. (Box 12, Folder 41-36)
    - "The Report of the President," Hamilton College Bulletin. Citation only. WHC did not keep a copy., 1939-1940 (Box 12, Folder 41-37)
    - Papers concerning Hamilton College public speaking training., 1940-1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-38)
    - "Hamilton College Admissions Manual." Oversize., 1941 (Box 12, Folder 41-39)
    - WHC letter to the New York Herald Tribune responding to Henry Grattan Doyle's pro-language point of view on education., 1942 Jan 12 (Box 12, Folder 42-1)
    - "A Ninety-Year Conflict Erupts Again," WHC article, Educational Record, pages 192-218., 1942 Apr (Box 12, Folder 42-2)
    - Newsclippings about 42-2., 1942 Jan-Sep (Box 12, Folder 42-2A)
    - Statement by WHC against the University of Chicago's two-year A.B. degree plan, Utica Observer-Dispatch., 1942 May 10 (Box 13, Folder 42-3)
    - "The War on the College," WHC article, Atlantic Monthly, pages 719-26., 1942 Jun (Box 13, Folder 42-4)
    - Correspondence about 42-4., 1942 May-Aug (Box 13, Folder 42-4A)
    - First draft of 42-4., undated (Box 13, Folder 42-4B)
    - "Three Problems of Liberal Education," transcript of WHC address to be delivered at Colgate University, but cancelled due to illness., 1942 Sep 24 (Box 13, Folder 42-5)
    - "The Importance of Mechanisms," WHC article, School and Society, pages 294-295., 1942 Mar 14 (Box 13, Folder 42-6)
    - "Hamilton's 131st Year," WHC address given on Opening Day, Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 4-9., 1942 Oct (Box 13, Folder 42-7)
    - WHC memo to Luce, Henry R. about John K. Jessup's article, "America and the Future," Life Magazine., 1942 Fall (Box 13, Folder 42-8)
    - "Our Misleading Universities," WHC article submitted to the Saturday Evening Post but rejected. Includes correspondence., 1942 Jan-Mar (Box 13, Folder 42-9)
    - WHC letter written for inclusion in book of letters to be presented to Dr. Charters, W. W. on his retirement., 1942 May 13 (Box 13, Folder 42-10)
    - "University Education in the United States," WHC article, Journal of Education, London, pages 446-447., 1942 Oct (Box 13, Folder 42-11)
    - "Fallacy of the Two-Year Degree," WHC article, University of Kansas Review, pages 23-32., 1942 Summer (Box 13, Folder 42-12)
    - Article, partially written by WHC in Survey Graphic, page 315., 1942 Jul (Box 13, Folder 42-13)
    - Correspondence with Hopkins, E.M. President of Dartmouth College., 1942 (Box 13, Folder 42-14)
    - WHC review of a Stanford Conference on The University and the Future of America., 1942 Mar (Box 13, Folder 42-15)
    - Summary of the 45 chapel sessions during the academic year, WHC, Hamilton College., 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 42-16)
    - Correspondence about the teaching loads of the Hamilton mathematics faculty., 1942 May-Aug (Box 13, Folder 42-16A)
    - Correspondence with Mac Diggs and Campbell, and Libs Dickson about the Dicksons' drinking problems., 1942 Jan-Jun (Box 13, Folder 42-16B)
    - "The University of Chicago Sophomore Degree," sent to the editors of the New York Times and published under the title, "Cowley Assails Hutchins Plan." Includes correspondence., 1942 May-Jul (Box 13, Folder 42-17)
    - "Democracy and Leadership," transcript of WHC radio talk, 7 pages., 1942 Jan 24 (Box 13, Folder 42-18)
    - WHC memo on the history of American higher education, with comments by Professor Graves, Edgar B.., 1942 Jan (Box 13, Folder 42-19)
    - Correspondence related to WHC's Carnegie Foundation grants., 1942-1955 (Box 13, Folder 42-20)
    - Papers related to WHC's chairmanship of the Warman-power Commission Committee on the use of the colleges during the war: (Box 13, Folder 42-21)
    - Initial proposals for college and university participation in the war effort., 1942 May-Aug (Box 13, Folder 42-21A)
    - Correspondence about proposals adopted by the Subcommittee of the Warmanpower Commission, and about the committee set up by WHC and others to address this problem, The Committee on the Relationship of Higher Education and the Federal Government., 1942 Aug-1945 Apr (Box 13, Folder 42-21B)
    - Correspondence with Snavely, Guy E. Executive Director of the Association of American Colleges. Includes copy of a letter from Roosevelt, Franklin to Snavely., 1942 Sep-Nov (Box 13, Folder 42-21C)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers., 1942 Jul-1944 Feb (Box 13, Folder 42-21D)
    - Correspondence with and about Conant, James B.. Includes WHC summary of his relationship with Conant., 1943-1950, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 42-22A)
    - Papers related to WHC proposal to Conant, James B. leading to the writing and publication of General Education in a Free Society by Buck, Paul H., Chairman of Harvard University., 1942 Dec-1943 Jun (Box 13, Folder 42-22B)
    - Correspondence with Plant, James S.., 1942-1946 (Box 13, Folder 42-23)
    - Letters about Hillsdale College address, given by WHC (No copy of speech.), 1942 Oct-Nov (Box 14, Folder 42-24)
    - Transcript of WHC address to District Two of the American Alumni Council, New York, 29 pages., 1942 Dec 7 (Box 14, Folder 42-25)
    - WHC's alumni fund pamphlet, inserted in the Hamilton Alumni Review, 8 pages., 1942 Mar (Box 14, Folder 42-26)
    - Article about Hamilton honorary degree citations given to Henry R. Luce, Bishop Coley, Chancellor Mangan, Count Sforza, Carl Carmer, in the Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 218-220., 1942 Jul (Box 14, Folder 42-27)
    - Hamilton College Trustees Report., 1942 Feb 28 (Box 14, Folder 42-28)
    - Hamilton College Trustees Report., 1942 Apr 18 (Box 14, Folder 42-29)
    - Hamilton College Trustees Report., 1942 May 22 (Box 14, Folder 42-30)
    - Hamilton College Trustees Report., 1942 Oct 10 (Box 14, Folder 42-31)
    - Note: Folders 42-26 through 42-31 are in bound volume with oversize items at the end of this series. (Box 14, Folder 42-32)
    - "Hamilton College Misellaneous Administrative Procedures," WHC., 1941-1942 (Box 14, Folder 42-32)
    - Correspondence with college presidents defending small liberal arts colleges. Most cite prominent alumni from their institutions., 1942 (Box 14, Folder 42-33)
    - "Education for War," WHC article, Fortune Magazine, pages 133-182., 1942 Dec (Box 14, Folder 42-34)
    - "Our Wartime Program," WHC article, Hamilton Alumni Review, pages 63-67., 1943 Jan (Box 14, Folder 43-1)
    - "Why Save Small Colleges, Anyway?" WHC article Hamilton Alumni Revew, pages 116-122., 1943 Mar (Box 14, Folder 43-2)
    - Hamilton College Board of Trustees Report, 15 pages., 1943 Jun 5 (Box 14, Folder 43-3)